http://www.hotfrog.info/index.php?zonename=privacynotice29

Data Privacy NoticeThe Parochial Church Council (PCC) of Holy
Trinity, Frogmore1. Your personal data –
what is it?Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified
from that data.  Identification can be by
the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data
controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing
of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the
“GDPR”), now implemented by the Data Protection Act 2018.2. Who are we? The PCC of Holy Trinity, Frogmore is the data controller (contact
details below).  This means it decides
how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.3. How do we process your
personal data?The PCC of Holy Trinity, Frogmore complies with its obligations under
the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it
securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by
protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure
and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect
personal data.We use your personal data for the
following purposes: -To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the
public within the parish of Holy Trinity, Frogmore and individuals who
associate themselves with Holy Trinity;To administer membership records; To fundraise and promote the interests of Holy Trinity, Frogmore
as a charity; To manage our employees and volunteers; To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing
of gift aid applications);To inform you of news, events,
activities and services running at Holy Trinity;To share your contact details with the
offices of the Deanery or the Diocese where you have accepted a role in
connection with those bodies on behalf of Holy Trinity, Frogmore.4. What is the legal basis
for processing your personal data?Legitimate
interest in you due to –Your
membership of one or more groups operating under the auspices of Holy Trinity,
Frogmore with processing restricted to the purposes of the group(s) in
question, or   Your
prior attendance at a Holy Trinity event similar to one we wish to inform you
about.Explicit
consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about parish news,
events, activities, marketing, fundraising and services and process your gift
aid donations and keep you informed about events outside the parish.Processing
is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or
social protection law, or a collective agreement;Processing
is carried out by Holy Trinity, Frogmore as a not-for-profit body with a
religious aim provided: -the
processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes);
and there
is no disclosure to a third party without consent.5. Sharing your personal dataYour personal data will be treated in strict confidence and will
only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service
to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with
third parties outside of Holy Trinity, Frogmore with your consent.6. How long do we keep your
personal data?We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide
“Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church
of England website [see contact details below].Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still
current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 7 years after
the tax year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages,
funerals) permanently.7. Your rights and your
personal data  Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the
following rights with respect to your personal data: -The right to request a copy of your personal data which the PCC of
Holy Trinity, Frogmore holds about you; The right to request that the PCC of Holy Trinity, Frogmore
corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;  The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no
longer necessary for the PCC of Holy Trinity, Frogmore to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time.The right to request that the data controller provide the data
subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data
directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability),
(where applicable) [Only applies where
the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a
contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes
the data by automated means].The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or
processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further
processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where
applicable) [Only applies where
processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in
the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and
processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners
Office.8. Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data
for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will
provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the
processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions.
Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new
processing.9. Contact DetailsTo exercise all relevant
rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Holy
Trinity, Frogmore Data Protection Lead at 01727 872667.You can contact the
Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe
House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF. Details about retention periods can currently be found
in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England website at: https://www.churchofengland.org/about-us/structure/churchcommissioners/administration/librariesandarchives/recordsmanagementguides.aspx
